We've spent 10 days talking about
the places you can go after
you
die because the world springs from
seeds in your
mind, so we'd better start again
with the pen. You've
heard this before, but I don't mind, we're going to
do it one
more time. We recently did this in Hong
Kong because so many people have
heard it
before. I taught those people how to teach
this in a more
fun way. So I'm going to teach you how to
teach
this. If you teach it
properly, the people
listening to you can't go to a bad place
after they
die. Why are we going to talk about this
for two
hours? But if you teach it properly,
the person
listening to you doesn't have to go to a bad
place after they die. In fact, it's
impossible. So it's important to
understand
this and be able to
teach it. Those of you who have
heard this many
times, I'm going to show and teach you how to
teach it.
Think about it: if you can help someone
not go to a bad place after they
die, it's probably one of the best
things you can do with your
life. So here's how to
teach it. First, we
teach about emptiness. We
often use the
pen and teach it.  asking
questions, and when I show it to him, I
ask Scott,
and I
say, "
Most countries were conquered
by the British in the
past, so I always joked about the
company, and I told them, 'I'm going to ask
questions.' I
showed this pen to some
executive vice presidents at
British Airways because there was a strike back then
that lasted for
years. They tried to implement a lot of
standard business training
to make it
work. So they were
desperate, and so they called in the
weirdest
business coaches. And then we went
to the sub-headquarters, which is at the airport, to
the
side. I'm
going to ask you
questions. Please answer me." I said, "Okay." "Yes, okay," I said. I
held up the
pen. "What is this?"
I asked, and they were
all afraid to answer.
So don't be like British
Airways. You are, and say your
country,
Mexico. The people of Mexico aren't
shy; they'll give you
answers. And if you're in China, you say, "
Oh, the Chinese aren't shy, and they'll
give you a good
answer."
The monastery
is very
small. If you want to make a joke,
you can
say, "Do Tibetan monks use
this?"
and you tell them, "No, it's not for
prayers; it's for tapping."  To the
students, and on the
head, your head gets
marks of
this on your
head. So you can tell the
vice presidents of British
Airways if you don't give me a good
answer, the first line receives the
ancient Tibetan treatment.
They understand
in the monastery it's like a
wedding, you throw the
rosary and whoever catches it has to stand up
and start
debating. Nobody wants to catch it.
First, what is
this? If only three people answer,
you have to ask the
question. I need an answer from the
audience, not three people
here. I don't know, because the first women
answer first. Also, can I hit those in the
back?
Is
that a
feather? If a small dog comes in
here, if you're on a stage, you can
sit on the edge of the
stage. If the dog approaches the
stage, you
show
the dog this.
Here,
silence, it would bite.
What is the next
question? Does the dog see this as a
feather? Does it
see it as a chew toy?
Who is right? The human or the dog? So
here, it's okay to explain. Why
can you write with
this? The human can use it. That's fine. It
's real for
both of you. Next question: what do I
do if I leave this?
Here, you have to make it
dramatic, don't...  Say no, don't tell them, it
happens, all the
people
happen, if they both come out, you have to
tell them in a way
to generate a
mental image, let's suppose they come out
and all the dogs
come out too, then you lower your tone of
voice, the room
is already there, you can't
find the door from the
outside, there are no
people or
dogs at that moment, at that moment
you have to say what is it,
you have to repeat the question, is it
a feather or something to
bite on? It's important to emphasize at
that moment what it
is, listen, we
teach in many countries,
we all over the world,
in the third line there is always a
smart woman and when you tell her what it is, what is it
at that
moment, then you have to pay
attention, the
correct answer is
nothing, and then you have to let yourself
read, all of you have heard about
emptiness,
Buddhists talk about emptiness
and from there you start to mention
three incorrect ideas of emptiness,
emptiness,
some
say it's all black, close your
eyes,
black, when I told that to my
teacher and he gave me
meaning
and asked me, do you have any
different idea, try not to have a single
thought in your
mind, that's the
care, I told that to my
Lama, I read  An American book
said that emptiness means not
thinking about
anything. If a dog enters your
mind,
let it, don't get attached. I did
n't hear a third idea in a
book. Oh, nothing
matters. If someone
hits you, don't be sad. If someone kisses you, do
n't be
happy.
Nothing is good.
Nothing is bad. There's
no need to worry about anything.
Good. If it feels
bad, it's an
illusion. My stupid god.
Then you return to the
table. When the people
left, and all the dogs
left too, there was nobody in the
room. It's not a
feather, nor a
chew toy. It's
empty. It's nothing. At that
moment, it's important.
And suppose a person
returns. They come to the
table. We both
return. How are you?
I'm
fine.
Cappuccino. Is that it?
What is it? It's at
that moment. Cappuccino.
What is that at that
moment? Something happens in your
mind. Up until that moment,
nothing. It wasn't a
feather,
nor can you tell. Halfway through, you see it.
You can. At that moment,
a seed opens in your
mind, and from that
seed emerges a small
image made of
light. It's made of light. That's the
size of an image of a
feather. It emerges from your
mind and imposes itself on this
stick.
Then you have to make the audience
respond to that.  The
moment it
becomes a feather for me,
then lift the
feather, hold it with the microphone in your
hand.
This is
true. Make sure the feather is
pointing
upwards. Don't do it like this, but like this, at this
angle. Then use your
hand. Everyone raise your
hand and
show me. Say, does
the feather come from the
feather or does the feather come from
me? Which
one? Show me. And they must answer
like this. Two of them, the back part,
doing this, it happens. It must
come from me. Next
question: Why?
Because if the dog entered before, what does it
become? If it came from
itself, the dog would see a
feather
that comes from the
dog's mind, and the feather comes from the human mind.
Correct? This is a
debate technique of
years. And so, amicably, it's
okay.
When they perceive that it's
okay, they can no longer go
back. In Tibet, it's like a game of
chess. Correct? It comes from me?
No? And that's when you've got them
for the rest of their
lives. Don't
forget, it comes from
me. Everything comes from you: the
feathers, the
buildings, the
lakes, your husband, your
wife. Everything comes from
you. If you know how to sow those
seeds, you can have what  I want to
tell you, look, this person, Michel, did
n't know anything about
business,
nothing. I saw him in a Buddhist monastery, without
knowing anything about
business. He started
this million-
dollar company and then it failed, it failed,
and he didn't make a
million-
dollar company. He didn't make a company with
annual sales of 250 million
dollars, the largest jewelry company
in the
world, acquired by Warren Buffett in
2009.
Maybe I can do
that. Maybe I can do
that. If you understand how to plant a
seed, a
beautiful
partner, good
health, when I was
50. Most people retire at
25. If you know how to plant a
seed, even inner peace.
There are like four people in the
audience: I don't want
money, I don't want a beautiful
wife. I don't need to do anything, I
just want
inner peace. Inner peace also comes
from
seeds. Spiderman, everyone in the
audience likes Spiderman.
Everyone wants to save the
world. It's important to say that if you
understand
seeds and if you understand how to
plant them, you can help everyone.
One
person can change the whole
world if they understand about
seeds deep within their
being. You want to save the
world? So no, no  Don't underestimate your
audience, no matter where you teach
or in what country,
whether they are
business executives or
yoga students. We all have three desires:
first, food;
second, sex; third, to
save the
world. The third is stronger than the
first
two. If you understand how to plant a
seed, you can help everyone.
Then pick someone in the
audience
and say, "Can you help me with
something, Juan
Bosco?" and say, "Would you help me plant
a
seed? Can you teach me how to teach?"
These people, plant a seed,
help
teach—so far, I haven't had anyone
say
no. Pick someone with a good
smile,
try to raise their hand
so everyone can
see it, and say, "Let's talk about
the four steps to planting a
seed." You can pause until the
crying babies are taken out, or you can have electrical tape with you
for a lecture.
Let's plant a
seed. There are four steps. Step number one:
Tell me what you
want. I want 000. Next
week I want to become
000. That's step one. The
second step is to find another
person who wants the
same thing. You have to  You have to emphasize this a lot.
This is where you really need to
emphasize to the audience that you ca
n't plant
a seed without another
person. If you're not willing to help
another person, you can't use the system. You have to get
tough here. Go away.
Right now, those who don't want to can
ask for a refund
later, and we'll tell them
no. If you don't want to help another
person, you can't use this
system. That's like
China. China
is trying to play baseball on a
floor. Karma has to bounce off the
other
person. Step number
two: Choose a person who wants the
same or almost the
same thing. You'd like to generate
money. And then, I'm already
happy. Don't forget to
talk about
that. I'm very
happy. I found another person to
help. Now I can plant the
seed. Without
him, I couldn't plant the seed.
Impossible. So when you find
someone who needs
something in this
system, you say, "
I found someone who wants
money," and you're
happy. And make sure they keep their arm
up and say, "Are you ready to plant
a seed?
Let's go." And here's where you have to be very
dramatic.
$ And here, you
close it and
release it like this. Open my
This is how you sow
karma. This is how you sow a
seed. If someone
explains it to you, you can
do it. Ready, one, two,
and then it's good to make a
sound. Bring the
microphone closer, and when my
hand opens, there's an image, a
photo, like a
video. My hand opens,
you can say it enters through the
window of my
eyes and touches my mind. That
image, my
hand, image of my
hand, image of my hand releasing, enters
through the window of my
eyes and touches my
mind. An
impression,
properly, makes an impression on my
mind, and that
impression becomes a
seed after two
hours. If you want to know, if you're interested in
knowing, it's called samsara in
Sanskrit. If you have
intelligent people like Mexicans,
you can delve
deeper. You generate an
impression on the
conscious mind. The movement, the
tortilla, here is the
conscious mind. Down here is the
subconscious. That
impression becomes a seed down here. There
you planted the
seed, and you have to be dramatic. The
person who received it did the demonstration
for you. They want to give it back,
but in a tone of, "No, I don't want it back. Do
you think I want it back?"
And then you go
back. "We're not
finished, don't forget,
you can change everything."
I like to talk about my
mom. She was the most generous woman I
ever
knew. She gave anything to
anyone who
asked. She had
children,
children, and her husband. She
was a school teacher. We didn't
have any
money, and one day,
five people left the
house for
school. One day I told my mom, "We have to
lock the front door
when you go to work and when we go
to school. We have to lock
the door." But why?
Because all the
other kids' parents lock the door.
And my mom
replied, "We can't do that. What
if someone is
hungry? They have to be able to get
in and open the
refrigerator, grab something, and then... I
got to the
refrigerator." And later, she let
homeless people sleep in our
bed. Sometimes I had to sleep on the
sofa. She even let others sleep in her bed.
And once she told me, "Do you remember
that man who came to sleep here? I had
no place to
sleep,
and I slept on the
sofa. He can't come
back." But why,
Mom? And she lifted her
pillow, and there was a loaded gun
under the
pillow. "I think he shouldn't come
back, so if this idea is
correct..."  If karma doubles every
day
when I give
$1, I can generate $1,000 in a
week. It will be
returned to me, delivered by the
universe, and I can't
stop it no matter where I
go. Even if I go to another
city, it does
n't matter where I go. Even if I die,
that karma will be
delivered
because you carry it
here in your
mind. Even if you die, the next
place you go, you will receive $
0. Nobody can
stop it. The audience feels
happy. He made $1,
and you have to say, "Don't forget to
take your wife to dinner tonight at the
French restaurant
here," and everyone is
happy, but you tell them, "But that's not
true." It's not all true. If
this were
true, my mom would be richer than Warren
Buffett. She gave everything, she gave
so much. Does it work? It's obvious that it doesn't
work. If this worked, everyone would do it.
But there's a
problem.
Many people... we see many people who give
and give away many things and are still
poor. My mom died poor.
And here's where you have to
confuse everyone.
Can you have some
chai? We can't... First, this
person told us that we can become
rich, and now...  He says we can't, you
say my
mom and then you tell them my mom never
learned the secret method,
step number four,
you have to teach it like this:
the first three
steps are for planting the
seed, but those seeds will remain
dormant for 100 years without
opening, you have to water them,
water the
seeds, you will have 000. Next
week you can create a company that
sells 300,000 diamonds
daily. If in
China you can say that my students
call it watering the seed, not like a
hen on an egg,
hatching is the fourth step. If you
know it, you can have anything you
want, you can have a relationship that
lasts 50 years.
48.
How do you have to water the
seed? How do you do
that?
Queen, you have to
meditate, you can do it
completely, we have to
do
special meditation, and don't do it like this:
first
left leg, then right,
then lie down on the sofa or something.
Before going to
sleep you have to
think about the good things you
are doing for other
people. If I really want 000
next
week, it is not enough to plant the
seed, I have to
water it.
Tonight I have to be happy about two
things  The
first one was very happy, I made him
happy.
Second, I'm happy that I'm trying
a new system to generate
money. It's much less stressful than
fighting with other people for
money. If it's true that this system is
real, the competition to generate
money is
wrong. The way to earn money is by
sharing it. You can use this
movement of
giving instead of
taking. The idea of ​​taking
money, of taking money from the
competition, is
wrong.
You can generate a $250
million company a
year by
sharing. And before going to
sleep, you have to water the
seed. If you don't,
nothing will
happen. The seed can open within
three
lifetimes.
If you want a seed that opens
quickly, like McDonald's fast food,
before going to
sleep, no, you're not allowed to be
worrying about your
life. I don't like it. My
husband, my boss told me I'm a
fool, my children are badly behaved.
That's the usual way for a person to
go to
bed, a person who plants
seeds. I did a good thing
today. I'm trying to earn
$0. I found someone to give
my money to. I'm very
happy. I found someone who is going to take
my
money. I want to earn $0 next
week. The happier you are, the
faster.  It will open the
seed. We're done with the
feather. That's the
feather. That's the long version of the feather story. You
can also do it in 5
minutes.